All right. So yeah, good morning, everyone.
So we have joined of the session two of this
project Q&A session series that we are currently
conducting. So you have joined these Super
Luminal Communication
teaching assistant for this project, as well
as the proxy client of the project. Before
we getting started, I would like to elaborate
about the project and give you a brief introduction
on the project topic. And let's move on to the
Q&A part, as well as the course, how the course
works and everything. So yeah, so as a start
I would like to take this topic and segregate
into three parts for the sake of understanding
it a little bit. So we are having this superluminal
communication voice codec. This is our project.
And if we try to elaborate about this superluminal
communication, this is what we are considering
communication faster than the light of the
speed. which currently doesn't exist and that's
why scientists were thinking of having at least
a relative solution for this one and from the
theoretical solution that they have provide
this wormholes. So the wormholes kind of thing
it's a tunnel created in the space where you
are allowed to travel from point A to point
B using this. It's like the, we can say it's
the shortest path that you can travel from place
A to place B in the space. But when we are
considering this one, it's obvious that at this
stage, it create such a wormhole and the size
of this wormhole could be very small where a
space shift and kind of things couldn't pass
by. So as the very first step we are trying
to build a program where we can transmit information
through this wormholes from place A to place
B. So in that case this is what we are going
to build and we are going to do it in a solution
of voice coding which means an audio we are
using audio for this one and this audio should
be encoded and decoded in order to
simply what you can see here is you're going
to build a your own program which has two functionalities.
First one encoding, the second one is decoding.
And this is how you can simply elaborate that.
And if I move forward so here it shows the complete
process of it. Once you input this file or
audio file dot wave file so it will pass through
your program and it will get encoded and say
like keep the file as the as a payload and then
you if we assume it is done from the point
A the one who receives this file or receives
your message in this voice dot wave file So
he can grab this payload.bin and then decode
it and get the voice output.wave file. So over
here, if you're wondering how we can measure
the compression here and the compression rate,
the formulas are given here. And based on this
compression rate, if you have joined the initial
kickoff meeting, I think Simon has nicely explained
this how the fidelity works with the compression
and you just have to find the sweet point in
between where we can maximize the fidelity
as well as the compression rate. So that's how
we are going to calculate this compression
and the accuracy of your work.
as an input which is audible which consists
of human voice and at the end of decoding that
you should be able to play it and understand
the message which consists in that file. So
accuracy level that sort of things we can use
for testing accuracy and higher the compression
rate is better with the But even though the
compression rate is high, it doesn't mean that
it's giving an accurate result at the end. So
it's your job here to identify the seed point
in between. Talking about the project aim, this
is what we are going to do, develop a highly
efficient voice encoder and decoder with. maximal
compression and high intelligibility which
means you should be able to play and understand
the message that consists in that file. So
these are some of the functional requirements
mentioned in the initial document. So you should
be able to create one file which it could be
either a Python script or a standalone executable.
So these are how you're going to do the encoding
step and the decoding step. You can name your
file as name.py or name.exe depending on the
script or the executable. You are going to
use.
enter this encode command with the input file
you will create the payload bit. Once you
give the decoding command and for this payload
bit you should be able to get the output.wav
file. Simply this is what you are going to do.
And moving forward this is some other functional
requirements that they have mentioned. If you
have any dependencies on your script or the
exe file you can zip everything together and
you can mention that as name.zip and it should
be run on a virtual machine running on windows
on asure and again.net sorry.wav file is a
single channel LPCM simplified at 44.1 kHz with
16 bits per sample consisting of human voice
audio. And these are the project deliverables
that we have articulated up to now. So you'll
be having a voice encoding algorithm and a decoding
algorithm and also you should be able to provide
a both these processes. Here I have some sample
user stories for you and these are just to
give you some sort of understanding on how to
write user stories. The method of writing it
like as a user I want to upload a.wav file to
codec so that I can encode the input file.
So if we can maintain this structure with the
acceptance criteria it would be great for your
projects since you are following the agile scrum
practice here. So yeah and the second one is
also as a user I want to encode the audio file
so that I can compress the input file. So acceptance
criteria for each and every user story is given
here and as a user I want to upload the output.wav
file so that I can receive the initial message
and the relevant acceptance criteria. So feel
free to change these user stories and you don't
have to stick to these three. You can create
how many user stories as you want and as per
the project requirement but this is like we
can say like a better practice of writing the
user stories. I'm pretty sure that you have
learned or will learn in upcoming sessions with
your lecturer. So yeah and other than that
I think yeah you if you have any questions up
to now regarding the project or how the things
will work on in the upcoming weeks just feel
free to raise those things. Yeah that will
come to the end of our presentation. Yeah feel
free to ask any questions if you have.
Hello. Hi. I have a question. So basically,
when we submit our algorithm, so when will
we test it? I mean, for accuracy on what parameter
it will be tested like? Up to now, accuracy,
that's some sort of it's mentioned here. So
you can follow this step. Oh. simply it should
be able to upload your voice file and up to
now this is up to now. So you should be able
to upload the file and once you have decoded
that file if you can replay that file and understand
the initial message that would be great and
with that you can you know make it as a percentage
over here. And you can compare that with the
compression rate that you have calculated.
So we can, like with many trials and errors,
you can get the compression rate and the accuracy
rate. So we can have an in-between, like, identify
the sweet point in between each of these.
Does it make sense? Yeah, it's OK. Yeah. I think
Simon also haven't mentioned any criteria,
right, for the fidelity in his presentation,
right? Yeah, what I understood, I mean, he's
like, that is a black box. We don't know. Yes,
yes, yes. So that is in the system. I mean,
the LPCM code, what they have written, it will
be written inside it. We don't know about the
parameter. Yes. So it's like a tricky part here,
but as I can recall, what he said is like,
there are some industry-free best practices
for the like calculating or, yeah, calculating
the fidelity levels, but he didn't mention such
like this, these parameters should be there
when you are testing that. Yeah, all right.
I mean, after some trials, we might find something
like some codes. Yes. Correct. Okay. Thank you.
Anyone else?
nothing from my laptop.
Anything you want to know about the upcoming
sessions and how the things are going to work?
Yes, like when will be the first meeting like
you will be the proxy client so when will be
the first official meeting with you and how
does that go?
I think that is as per the calendar provided
that should be started from
19th August as per my understanding. because
that's where, sorry, 12th August, it's the
beginning of the sprint. And yeah, from there
onwards, we are having like bi-weekly meetings
where we discuss about the sprint, upcoming
sprint and the retrospective, both functions
together. It will start on 12th August as per
the calendar.
And which way of communication is more convenient
for you, teams or a group? I'll be creating
some team groups for you. Or
if, yeah, I think I can create some team groups
for you. That I need to discuss further with
Dr. Amali as well. Last time what we did was
I created the group and included every member.
So I hope that. practice will continue in this
course as well. Yeah.
And I should mention this one as well. So for
the upcoming sessions, you will have to create
a Zoom or Teams link and share that with me.
It's totally on your hands to conduct the meetings
and ask the questions and clarify the things.
It's totally up to you.
I'm here as the proxy client give you the information
or discuss with our client and provide the
necessary information and working through the
sprint planning and review meetings. So yeah,
once you are in groups, you can share the meeting
link with me. So on a given slot that I'm providing.
And from there onwards, we can have the meetings.
All good. OK. Hi. Is my audio working or anything?
Yes, yes, Natalie. OK. So what you said is
the meetings with you are bi-weekly starting
the 19th. I just want to clarify. Oh, sorry.
It will start the 12th. Yes. Oh, 12th, sorry.
Yes. But this is with you, right? But does
our group ourselves, should we start meeting
ourselves and start documenting sprints? the
form meeting with you? Yeah. Yes. Yeah. Feel
free to work on like, if you, if you want to
figure the things out, feel free to have a meeting
with your own colleagues. Right. The official
meetings will start on from 12th August onward
as per the calendar. Yes. So, but before that,
if you want to get like, get familiar with each
other and, you know, discuss about how, how
the. planning things should go on, just feel
free to arrange a meeting, but I won't participate
that. I will participate from 12 August or what.
Is it a per group basis or? Yeah, yeah, you
will get a dedicated slot for like, it won't
change. So discuss with your friends and. I
think it's mandatory to participate everyone
for the meeting, the bi-weekly meetings. So
if someone is unable to participate, he or she
should let the TA or the course coordinator
know about it with valid reasons. And yeah.
So are the times for the meeting this 12th?
Like are they out? Where can I find this information?
Oh yeah, that information I think will be provided
by end of this week. I will have a chat with
Dr. Amali on that. Okay. And I, you know, pass
these things and mainly I think once the groups
are created, those things will be communicated
with you and share an Excel sheet, maybe like
we did last time. So you can allocate your,
select a time slot and keep it for each and
every meeting and you know, create a meeting
link and share that with me for the selected
times. Okay. So for, for the first meeting,
you will pick the time it will be provided,
but from then onwards, it's like flexible.
We can try to arrange any time. You mean like
once selected, can we change that? Uh, Oh,
I'm just wondering like the, the time for this,
this 12th, the 12th of Monday. Is that one
we, do we select this time or this is provided
by you? This, uh, I will provide a set of slots
based on my availability. Okay. So you can pick
one of them. Okay. So I'll just like keep,
keep an eye out until the end of this week and
the information will be written. Yes. Okay.
Yeah. I'll have a chat with Dr. Amali and, uh,
decide how we can, um, pass the information
as soon as possible. Okay. Thank you. Okay.
Anyone else?
Any other questions?
And if you are comfortable, would you please
let me know from which groups that you are
coming? I just want to make a note on that.
Our group number has to be updated. You can
put it on the chat. No, actually there is an
issue with our group. We are in one group,
Duggie, Shukash and Miyakelesh. Amali has assigned
us as an undergraduate group, but I have already
emailed her and got a reply. She will be updating
it. For now, if you look at the sheet, it is
the last undergraduate group. Okay. I think
she has updated now. No, she has not updated
the sheet. She has updated the local record
she mentioned on the email. For now it is codec
ug06, but it would be codec ug03. Okay, alright.
All are from the same group. Oh yeah, Nathaniel
has dropped that. Okay, cool.
Anything else you want to know, you are interested
to know.
I'm just curious about the documentation of
writing the sprints and the meetings. Does
that start next week, the official documentation
and report writing? Report one, I think. Yeah,
first report is scheduled on 12th August onward.
I think it's available now. You can have a
look on the homepage and go to the fourth week.
the initial report that you need to submit.
The deadline of it.
Yeah, I'm not sure that. But, um, uh, as separate
to the report, right? We have to keep track
of and document our day, uh, weekly meetings
and, uh, sprints and scrums, right? Yeah. So
this next week starts next week. Nothing to
write about this week. Uh, this week, I think,
uh, this is the third week, right? So, uh, only
the quiz is. available as the assignment. Right.
And from the fourth week onwards, there are
three assignments as initial report, question,
sorry, quiz four and the snapshot 1.1. Yeah.
So like there's nothing to document for this
week specifically. Nothing. Yeah. Yes. Yeah.
Okay. Just checking. Thank you. As for the
calendar, yes. There's nothing.
So since we are officially starting on 12 August,
just you can go through the materials that
you have provided and these have a little discussion
with your teammates and how things going to
work.
after a few weeks, one or two members are missing.
So it's better if you can, you know, get together
and like share the things with each member,
make sure the deadlines are met and the submissions
are done on time. Yeah, I think the GitHub reports
last time it was provided from the TA's side.
I hope it will be the same for this time as
well. So yeah, I have to discuss that with
Delta Amali and we'll let you know about it
by the end of the week. And from my side, I
have to provide my availability for the upcoming
sessions and the githubs.
Okay, yeah. Anything else?
And another thing, once you are allocated or
put into the Teams group, you can use that
platform to clarify the questions that you have
with me. I will be responding to those things
within 24 hours as soon as possible. And other
than that, you can, you know, I think you have
a corner in your reports to the questions that
you asked from your client, right?
As I can remember, there was. So when you're
asking those questions in the chat, you can
use those questions in your own report as well
as the questions that you ask from your clients
to clarify on the project. Yeah.
If you don't have any other questions we can
wind up the session. Meanwhile if you get more
questions with upcoming work just feel free
to reach me. You can find my email in the home
page and if there's any course related ones
you can reach to Dr. Mahali.
Alright.
Okay then. Shall we wind up? Does anyone have
questions? No questions, thank you. Thank you
very much. No worries at all. Okay. See you
then in upcoming sessions. All right, see you.
Thank you. Yeah, bye. Thank you.